Courage is immortal.
Mortal is a action, fantasy, thriller film directed by André Øvredal.
A young boy must discover the origins of his extraordinary powers before he is captured
by authorities hell-bent on condemning him for an accidental murder.
Eric, played by Nat Wolff.
Christine, played by Iben Akerlie.
Henrik, played by Per Frisch.
Hathaway, played by Priyanka Bose.
Ole, played by Arthur Hakalahti.
PST Officer, played by Kai Kolstad Rødseth.
Mortal (Norwegian: Torden) is a 2020 fantasy action film
co-written and directed by André Øvredal.
The film is inspired by Norse mythology, and stars Nat Wolff.
It is supported by a grant from the Government of Norway.
The film's dialogue is in English and Norwegian, and most of the actors are
Norwegian with the exception of Wolff and Priyanka Bose.
The film's original music by Marcus Paus was nominated for the Amanda Award and was
the Norwegian nominee for the Nordic Film Music Days – HARPA Award.
Mortal was released in Norway on 28 February 2020, by Nordisk Films, in the United Kingdom on 20
August, by Signature Entertainment, and in the United States on 10 November, by Saban Films.
It received mixed reviews from critics.
The tone is intense.